lyreco.com 2019-11-04

# LYRECO - GDPR Privacy Notice

## GDPR Privacy Notice

This notice explains what personal data (information) we will hold about you, how we collect it, and how we will use and may share information about you during the application process. We are required to notify you of this information, under data protection legislation. Please ensure that you read this notice (sometimes referred to as a ‘privacy notice’) and any other similar notice we may provide to you from time to time when we collect or process personal information about you.

Lyreco SAS (‘Company’) is a ‘data controller’ and gathers and uses certain information about you. This information is also used by our affiliated entities and group companies (our ‘group companies’) and so, in this notice, references to ‘we’ or ‘us’ mean the Company and our group companies.

We will comply with the data protection principles when gathering and using personal information, as set out in our Employee Privacy policy.

We may collect the following information, where appropriate, up to and including the shortlisting stage of the recruitment process:

  * Your name and contact details (ie address, home and mobile phone numbers, email address);

  * Details of your qualifications, experience, employment history (including job titles, salary and working hours) and interests;

  * Your racial or ethnic origin, sex and sexual orientation, religious or similar beliefs;

  * Details of your referees.

We may collect the following information, here appropriate, after the shortlisting stage, and before making a final decision to recruit:

  * Information about your previous academic and/or employment history, including details of any conduct, grievance or performance issues, appraisals, time and attendance, from references obtained about you from previous employers and/or education providers;

  * Information regarding your academic and professional qualifications;

  * Information regarding your criminal record;

  * Your nationality and immigration status and information from related documents, such as your passport or other identification and immigration information;

  * Information relating to your health;

  * A copy of your driving licence.

You may be required (by law or in order to enter into your contract of employment) to provide some of the information above to us to enable us to verify your right to work and suitability for the position.

We may collect this information from you, your referees (details of whom you will have provided), your education provider, any relevant professional body, and any relevant governmental bodies.

We will typically collect and use this information for the following purposes (other purposes that may also apply are explained in our Employee Privacy policy:

  * to take steps to enter into a contract;

  * for compliance with a legal obligation;

  * for the performance of a task carried out in the public interest

  * for the purposes of our legitimate interests or those of a relevant third party (such as a benefits provider), but only if these are not overridden by your interests, rights or freedoms

  * because it is necessary for carrying out obligations or exercising rights in employment law; and

  * for reasons of substantial public interest (preventing or detecting unlawful acts).

We seek to ensure that our information collection and processing is always proportionate.

We may also need to share some of the above categories of personal information with other parties, such as HR consultants and professional advisers. Usually, information will be anonymised but this may not always be possible. The recipient of the information will be bound by confidentiality obligations. We may also be required to share some personal information with our regulators or as required to comply with the law.

Information may be held at our offices and those of our group companies, and third party agencies, service providers, representatives and agents as described above.

We keep the personal information that we obtain about you during the recruitment process for no longer than is necessary for the purposes for which it is processed. How long we keep your information will depend on whether your application is successful and you become employed by us, the nature of the information concerned and the purposes for which it is processed.

We will keep recruitment information (including interview notes) for no longer than is reasonable, taking into account the limitation periods for potential claims such as race or sex discrimination (as extended to take account of early conciliation), after which they will be destroyed. If there is a clear business reason for keeping recruitment records for longer than the recruitment period, we may do so but will first consider whether the records can be pseudonymised, and the longer period for which they will be kept.

If your application is successful, we will keep only the recruitment information that is necessary in relation to your employment. For further information, see Employee Privacy policy

Where our processing of your information is based solely on our legitimate interests (or those of a third party), you have the right to object to that processing if you give us specific reasons why you are objecting, which are based on your particular situation. If you object, we can no longer process your information unless we can demonstrate legitimate grounds for the processing, which override your interests, rights and freedoms, or the processing is for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.

Please contact our Global Data Protection Officer (DPO), **Cedric** **Voisin** _[privacy.office@lyreco.com](mailto:privacy.office@lyreco.com)_ if (in accordance with applicable law) you would like to correct or request access to information that we hold relating to you or if you have any questions about this notice. You also have the right to ask our Data Protection Officer for some but not all of the information we hold and process to be erased (the ‘right to be forgotten’) in certain circumstances. Our Data Protection Officer will provide you with further information about the right to be forgotten, if you ask for it.

We have appropriate security measures in place to prevent personal information from being accidentally lost, or used or accessed in an unauthorised way. We limit access to your personal information to those who have a genuine business need to know it. Those processing your information will do so only in an authorised manner and are subject to a duty of confidentiality.

We also have procedures in place to deal with any suspected data security breach. We will notify you and any applicable regulator of a suspected data security breach where we are legally required to do so.

**What data we keep – Talent Pooling**

If you apply for a role and we do not process your details for that particular opening, but instead your details are selected for one of our ‘talent pools’, we will keep hold of your data provided so that we can contact you for future opportunities. We may also contact you periodically to update you on other possible suitable opportunities, this will also be the case if you subscribe to ‘job alerts’ via your candidate home account.

If you submit your details through one of job listings for future opportunities within a particular business area type, we may also hold onto your data and contact you regarding future possible opportunities. You may also be ‘invited to apply’ for a particular role that we identify as suitable. This will also be the case if you subscribe to ‘job alerts’ via your candidate home account.

**Unsuccessful applications & data purging **

Please note, if your application is not successful and we do not add your details to our secure talent pools, your data will be removed from our system within a period of 30 days.

**Data removal & purging**

If you wish to remove your information/data from our database at any point you can do so via your Candidate Home Account within the Lyreco Careers environment. To do this simply seclect ‘Account Settings’ and follow the options to delete all of your information/data. You can also request for your data to be removed at any point by contacting us on the mentioned email, **_[privacy.office@lyreco.com](mailto:privacy.office@lyreco.com)_** or via your candidate home account

We hope that our Data Protection Officer can resolve any query or concern you raise about our use of your information. If not, contact the Information Commissioner at _https://ico.org.uk/concerns/_ or telephone: 0303 123 1113 for further information about your rights and how to make a formal complaint.
